Branden Millward

Lead Analyst

Contact

Address

Ilkeston, Derbyshire, DE7 4SF

Phone

07471684393

Fmail

branden.millward@gmail.com

LinkedIn

http://www.linkedin.com/in/branden-millward

Website

https://brandenmillward.github.io/

Skills

Stakeholder management Business process mapping Strategic planning Statistical analysis Requirements gathering Predictive modelling Data Analysis

Programming Languages

Python

R

C++

SAS

Java

C#

Tools

Microsoft Office

Tableau

Visio

Jira

Figma

GIT

Qlikview

Skilled Lead Analyst with a record of success breaking down and improving business systems and processes. Collaborates well to test, implement, refine and enhance systems and meet current and expected business needs. Excellent research, reporting and communication skills with a strong technical background

Experience

Current – July 2021

Lead Analyst | October 2021 - Present Senior Analyst | July 2021 - October 2021

Post Office – Chesterfield

- Promoted within a 4-month timeframe for exceeding goals and supporting leadership.
- Manage 2 teams of analysts across multiple work streams across the Horizon Improvements program
- Plan and priorities work from various stakeholders for sprints to meet deadlines.
- Write recommendation decks to be presented to CIO and other senior stakeholders from multiple business areas.
- Produce User and Data Journey maps to identify As-Is and new To-Be processes.
- Identify problems with the current process and create recommendations to remediate these problems by working closely with Product Owners, Postmasters and other stakeholders of each product

Jun 2021 – Jul 2020

Data Analyst

Capital One - Nottingham

- Designed and implemented a new communications strategy that is sent to customers in arrears and hardship
- Investigated and identified customers affected by errors in processes and made the recommendation for remediation, and implemented updates to the process
- Built and generate reports for various deep dives and investigations

Jun 2020 – Sep 2018

Business/Strategy Analyst

Capital One - Nottingham

- Developed a new monitoring process to incorporate data from across the entire UK acquisitions business by rebuilding the legacy model monitoring process, reducing analyst time from 2 weeks to 3 days and monitoring accuracy from 66% to 97%
- Increased customer engagement and payer rates through a test of modifying communication frequency and type. That was later fully rolled out following positive results
- Managed the entirety of the Acquisition Valuations monitoring process for the UK business, including data gathering and building the reports to present to senior leadership.
- I developed a monitoring process to predict the outcomes of customers accepted on a payment holiday and how that would affect the arrears rates for the following year.

Jun 2017 -Jul 2016

Junior Business Analyst

GKN Driveline - Redditch

- Managed the complete system life cycle of a new ERP system for the Commercial and Finance teams
- Engaged with clients to gather requirements and built new QilkSense and Qlikview dashboards and tools
- Tested and reviewed new systems and tools and ensure they met the client's needs and requirements before deciding to push them to live

Education

Current – Aug 2021	MSc Artificial Intelligence - Current average: Distinction University of Bath – Bath
Jul 2018 – Sep 2014	 BSc (H) Computer Science SW – 1st Class Hons Nottingham Trent University – Nottingham Dissertation: Comparing Two Machine Learning Methods to form a Hybrid Machine Learning Method
	 Awarded: Certificate of Professional Practice
	• Elected to Course Rep for Computer Science in years 2014-18
Jul 2014 – Sep 2012	3 A-Levels in Mathematics, Physics and Computing; AS-Level in Further Mathematics NULC – Newcastle Under Lyme
Jul 2012 – Sep 2007	10 GCSEs A*-C Including Mathematics & English 2 B-TECs at Distinction St Thomas More Catholic College – Stoke-on-Trent

Certifications

Jul 2021	IBM Applied AI Specialization - IBM
Jun 2021	Artificial Intelligence Foundations Specialization - IBM
May 2021	Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals Al-900 – Microsoft

References

Caroline Langensiepen Senior Lecturer at Nottingham **Trent University** caroline@rjccsl.co.uk

John Beat EA Programme Manager John.Beat@gkndriveline.com 07876626565